Linear search, linear search is a sequential searching algorithm where we start from one end and check
every element of the list until the desired element is found.
It is the simplest searching algorithm the time complexity of this linear search depend on, and which
is the number of elements found on an array or any type of data structure that we are going to search
in a linear for.
And the space complexity is of one, because we don't need any memory for that, just for searching
a specific.
Element, let's talk an example about searching for an element in Iraq if we need to find an element
40 in array, which is they're containing 10, 20, 30, 40 and 50.
We start from zero index zero element and we search all the elements until we found for.
So for 40 is founded.
So return the index like three.
Or if we are making functions that returns Boolean it is containing or not, then it will return for
true.
OK, now let's see the contra like the opposite example, like finding the Element 100 in the same array
10, 20, 30, 40.
We start from here and we start searching for 100 and we didn't found it.
So we go through all the elements of this array, so we searched and elements.
If we have five, then we have searched five elements.
If we have one million element in this array, we need to search one million elements so it will return
minus one or return false according to their return and type of the function that you right?
OK.
So let's see the linear search in C language and in the next video, we are going to implement the linear
search in Java.
We start by making that insert a method that took into that parameters that relate that we are going
to search in it that aren't N and the size of Earth and the index that we are search.
We are going to search for it.
So going through an array sequentially, we start by making a for loop.
For an entire year equal to zero, I less than an hour plus plus oil because we are going through all
the elements, so we need A-plus.
Plus, if the array at the index are equal, equal to zero, then return.
I so would return the index of the element that we have searched for.
Otherwise, it were returned minus one because we have here that int array and search method that it
is returning type of this.
Method.
Then we need to test it.
We in the main we create the array.
Two four zero one nine and X equal to one.
So we are going to search for one and and is the size of the array how to calculate it at a very simple
size of array.
And over the size of a rate at the next year, now we start by end result equal to search, so we store
inside a variable called result that returning the returning value of the search function, which is
array.
And we passed and and we pass X. Then we may test the result if it is equal, equal minus one, then
print element not found.
So it will not, but it will print for us, not element, not found.
If we don't have this, Congress will pass an element that is not found in theory otherwise.
So this notation, this writing the question mark and this this is in case check this condition if it
is true.
So if it is true, then make the element not found otherwise.
If this.
If this condition result equal minus one is not true, then we print element found and index percentage
the and the result, which is the index where we find that.
OK.
Now the.